MELISSA J WOMACK

Phone: (512) 568-5185

Address: 7510 E Grand Ave, Apt 3322, Dallas, TX 75214

GitHub: https://github.com/Melissajwomack

Portfolio: https://melissajwomack.github.io/portfolio-v2/

Email: m.womack010101@gmail.com

Summary

M.S. graduate student in bioinformatics and computational biology. Anticipated graduation date of May 2021. Focused on improving skills in programming, algorithm analysis, and data engineering. Previous military experience where I gained soft skills in teamwork, discipline, and adaptability.

Skills

• C++

CSS

• SQL

• Git/GitHub

- JavaScript HTML
- Node.JSjQuery
- MongoDBPython

MacOS/Linux/WindowsMicrosoft Office

Certifications

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

July 2018 - Oct 2018

The University of Texas at Austin

 Curriculum included: MERN Stack, Agile Methodology, API Integration, Responsive Web Design, Git/GitHub, Heroku, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, React.JS, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, and MySQL

Education

Master of Science in Bioinformatics and Computational Biology

Aug 2019 - Present

The University of Texas at Dallas, GPA - 3.61

Bachelor of Science in Microbiology

Aug 2015 – May of 2018

Texas State University, GPA – 3.76, magna cum laude

Relevant Coursework

- Algorithm Analysis and Data Structures
- Combinatorics and Graph Theory
- Advanced Calculus and Linear Algebra
- Web Programming Languages Spring 2021
- Computer Science
- Probability and Statistics for Data Science
- Machine Learning Spring 2021
- Database Design Spring 2021

Experience

Graduate Student Research

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

University of Texas at Dallas, Dallas, TX

- Comparative genomics study of bacterial samples from postmenopausal women with chronic or recurrent urinary tract infections
- Developed skills in bash, scripting, data analytics, communication and project development

Microbiology Technician

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

Clinical Pathology Laboratories, Austin, TX

- Processed and handled over 200 clinical samples a day while adhering to safety protocols and ensuring quality control
- Assisted in the identification of clinically relevant organisms using a wide array of biochemical tests

Veterinary Food Inspection Specialist

April 2007 - Oct 2015

United States Army

- Collaborated in creating and implementing a database that kept track of 9.3 million dollars of inventory
- Performed the inspection of food designed for human consumption and assisted veterinarians with animal medicine